# Stephanie H Jones

8479 south Hodgeson Rd Gonzales, La 70737 (225) 938-8906 sjones.njones@gmail.com

## Summary

I am a passionate, patient, creative, and dedicated teacher with 6 years of experience teaching both online and in the classroom. I have experience creating and maintaining inventories for the chemistry department at a major university. I have a Bachelors of Science in Chemistry as well as a Masters of Education. I am currently seeking to transition from the field of education to pursue engaging work as a Virtual Assistant.

# Highlights

- Extremely organized
- Attention to detail
- Initiative to work independently
- Quick learner

- Strategic thinker
- Excellent analytical skills
- Dedicated
- Microsoft Office, Excel, PowerPoint proficiency

# Experience

#### Cashier's Assistant

Costco, Baton Rouge, LA

October 2021 - Currently Employed

- Addressing and following up on all customer queries
- Ensuring accuracy in the processing of members' orders
- Actively engaging in Costco's promotional activities and other sales events

## **Professional Test Scorer**

Pearson Testing Services, Remote

March 2018 - Currently Employed

- Work remotely to score standardized math tests for middle school and high school students
- Maintain a 99.9 % accuracy rating for test scoring

ESL Teacher VIPKID, Remote

April 2018 – October 2021

- Privately teach English to students of all English Language Proficiency levels online
- Develop rapport with families in China and their children through virtual means
- Submit timely and effective feedback after each lesson
- Received positive parent feedback from over 2,573 parents

## **Chemistry Teacher**

Zachary Community Schools, Zachary, LA

August 2009 – May 2012

- Taught 11th grade students basic concepts of chemistry and critical thinking skills
- Planned, prepared, and facilitated laboratory experiments to give students hands-on experience
- Assessed students through exams, lab reports, and small-group performance

#### Teacher's Assistant / Laboratory Supplies Manager

Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, LA

January 2008 – April 2008

- Developed and maintained new chemical inventory system
- Organized chemistry stockroom
- Lectured about procedures and theories relevant to class experiments
- Supervised and assisted students during experiments
- Assessed lab reports and exams for understanding and misconceptions

# Education

# Masters of Arts in Teaching: Secondary Education, 2009

## Louisiana State University - Baton Rouge, LA

Academic Achievements: GFT Fellowship

Masters Research Project: The Effect of Student-Generated Graphic Organizers on Accuracy and Confidence in Ionic and Covalent Compound Naming, Adviser: Dr. Pamela Blanchard

Abstract Summary: The purpose of this study was to determine if there are any advantages to teaching with student-generated graphic organizers rather than teacher-generated graphic organizers in regards to naming ionic and covalent compounds. Through a mixed methods study the qualitative and quantitative data were collected from high school chemistry students from a small public high school in a rural town. The analysis of the data suggests no effect of student-generated graphic organizers on the students' ability to complete written problems concerning the naming of ionic or covalent compounds.

Bachelor of Science: Chemistry, 2007

#### Louisiana State University - Baton Rouge, LA

Academic Achievements: Louisiana TOPS Scholarship

Courses: General Chemistry Lecture and Lab, Biochemistry, Organometallic Chemistry, Advanced Inorganic Lecture and Lab, Physical Chemistry Lecture and Lab, Analytical Chemistry Lecture and Lab, Physics Lecture and Lab, Basic and Intermediate Organic Chemistry Lecture and Lab, Experimental Instrumentation for Characterization of Organic Compounds, Graphic Representation of Scientific Knowledge, Educational Theory